<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyril Lay</title>
    <link>http://www.lays.pro/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cyril Lay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.lays.pro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/post/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/post/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, I am Cyril Lay, welcome to my website. Let me introduce myself quickly below !
I work as a software engineer contractor, specialized in data. I provide services for conceiving, creating or enhancing diverse applications and programs.
Fond of computers since my early age, I obtained a degree in computer science, with a specialization in data mining. In order to learn how to use my machine learning knowledge on today&amp;rsquo;s high volumes of data, I worked as a data engineer and ML engineer for a year and a half, before starting to work independently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog posts</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/blog/blog-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/blog/blog-summary/</guid>
      <description> Detecting bot traffic on a webserver Building an image classification inference API in 30 minutes with deep learning Deep Fake Detection Challenge (DFDC) on Kaggle (draft) Plant Pathology Challenge Kaggle (draft)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/post/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/post/references/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Cyril enthusiastically approaches complex problems and is able to think through them clearly. Cyril is a good listener and seeks out feedback to improve. He works well in teams and is able to explain complicated ideas succinctly to team members on the business and technical sides. I was impressed by how quickly Cyril learned and how self directed he was. Cyril was also involved in some presentations to partners and clients where he represented the company very well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/post/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/post/services/</guid>
      <description>Creation of end-to-end machine learning pipelines with your data Training automation, deployment (cloud/on-premises) and monitoring Improving your existing pipelines : boost your models performances (training, accuracy and inference) Adding monitoring tools for your production applications Work with your data scientists to scale their code and increase their productivity and efficiency, generate training datasets  Latest work  Fixing and deploying a chabot marketplace on IBMCloud Foundry (The Conversation Consultancy) Built internal big data pipelines for business intelligence (MyTraffic) Helped in developing a high-scale ad trafic forecasting tool (Gumgum Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skillset</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/post/skillset/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/post/skillset/</guid>
      <description>   Data engineering Data science Cloud     Scala, Spark, SQL, Hadoop, Kafka, Airflow Python, Keras, SK-Learn, Open-cv, Fast.ai, R AWS (S3, EMR, ECS, EC2, Lambda, Redshift), Docker, Unix/Bash    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Fake Detection Challenge (DFDC) on Kaggle</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/blog/dfdc-challenge-kaggle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 03:08:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/blog/dfdc-challenge-kaggle/</guid>
      <description>[DRAFT - WORK IN PROGRESS]  Deep fake context, GAN, dataset size challenge etc processing the videos Frame extraction Face recognition ResNext50 training Inference pipeline : video -&amp;gt; frames -&amp;gt; faces -&amp;gt; prediction over each face/frame -&amp;gt; average -&amp;gt; output  Classifying genuine and fake videos (generated by a GAN) from a 500GB dataset. I processed the videos to reduce the dataset size, by first extracting a few frames per video, than performing image segmentation to extract the faces contained in the frames, which happened to contain glitches generated by the GAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plant Pathology Challenge Kaggle</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/blog/plant-kaggle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 02:27:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/blog/plant-kaggle/</guid>
      <description>[DRAFT - WORK IN PROGRESS] In this kaggle competition, we will learn how to train a convolutional neural network (CNN) for multi label classification.
Problem statement Misdiagnosis of the many diseases impacting agricultural crops can lead to misuse of chemicals leading to the emergence of resistant pathogen strains, increased input costs, and more outbreaks with significant economic loss and environmental impacts. Current disease diagnosis based on human scouting is time-consuming and expensive, and although computer-vision based models have the promise to increase efficiency, the great variance in symptoms due to age of infected tissues, genetic variations, and light conditions within trees decreases the accuracy of detection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting bot traffic on a webserver</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/blog/bot-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/blog/bot-detection/</guid>
      <description>This article is still a draft.
Introduction The goal of this project was to create a POC for a bot detection system, by using a data file containing all HTTP requests to a server. I started by browsing and skimming through a few technical and scientific papers and resources to gather knowledge on how bot detection is done when applied to HTTP logs, those resources will be linked at the bottom of this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/imprint-gdpr/gdpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/imprint-gdpr/gdpr/</guid>
      <description>GDPR information are highly specific to the site. You may use a generator, e.g. Datenschutz-Generator</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprint</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/imprint-gdpr/imprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/imprint-gdpr/imprint/</guid>
      <description>Information according to ยง 5 TMG
first and last name address
Contact: Phone: phone number E-Mail: e-mail address
Responsible for content according to ยง 55 Abs. 2 RStV: first and last name address
Disclaimer: Content Liability The contents of our pages were created with great care. However, we can not assume any liability for the accuracy, completeness and timeliness of the content. As a service provider we are responsible according to ยง 7 Abs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an image classification inference API in 30 minutes with deep learning</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/blog/inference-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/blog/inference-api/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I built a simple inference API backed by the famous pretrained CNN model ResNet50. The network is 50 layers deep and can classify images into 1000 object categories, such as keyboard, mouse, pencil, and many animals. Currently, the API is running on the same machine hosting this website : a simple t2.micro on AWS EC2. It is available at http://datascience.lays.pro.
UI   Architecture   Command line usage Download an image, and submit it with :</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>