<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sections on Cyril Lay</title>
    <link>http://www.lays.pro/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sections on Cyril Lay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.lays.pro/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/post/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/post/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, I am Cyril Lay, welcome to my website. Let me introduce myself quickly below !
I work as a software engineer contractor, specialized in data. I provide services for conceiving, creating or enhancing diverse applications and programs.
Fond of computers since my early age, I obtained a degree in computer science, with a specialization in data mining. In order to learn how to use my machine learning knowledge on today&amp;rsquo;s high volumes of data, I worked as a data engineer and ML engineer for a year and a half, before starting to work independently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/post/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/post/references/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Cyril enthusiastically approaches complex problems and is able to think through them clearly. Cyril is a good listener and seeks out feedback to improve. He works well in teams and is able to explain complicated ideas succinctly to team members on the business and technical sides. I was impressed by how quickly Cyril learned and how self directed he was. Cyril was also involved in some presentations to partners and clients where he represented the company very well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/post/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/post/services/</guid>
      <description>Creation of end-to-end machine learning pipelines with your data Training automation, deployment (cloud/on-premises) and monitoring Improving your existing pipelines : boost your models performances (training, accuracy and inference) Adding monitoring tools for your production applications Work with your data scientists to scale their code and increase their productivity and efficiency, generate training datasets  Latest work  Fixing and deploying a chabot marketplace on IBMCloud Foundry (The Conversation Consultancy) Built internal big data pipelines for business intelligence (MyTraffic) Helped in developing a high-scale ad trafic forecasting tool (Gumgum Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skillset</title>
      <link>http://www.lays.pro/post/skillset/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.lays.pro/post/skillset/</guid>
      <description>   Data engineering Data science Cloud     Scala, Spark, SQL, Hadoop, Kafka, Airflow Python, Keras, SK-Learn, Open-cv, Fast.ai, R AWS (S3, EMR, ECS, EC2, Lambda, Redshift), Docker, Unix/Bash    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>